<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2023 on Dr. Manika Lamba</title>
    <link>https://manika-lamba.github.io/categories/2023/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2023 on Dr. Manika Lamba</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://manika-lamba.github.io/categories/2023/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to better engage with ASIS&amp;T members? Lessons learned from SIG-III activities during the COVID-19 pandemic</title>
      <link>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/24/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/24/</guid>
      <description>



&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract
  &lt;a href=&#34;#abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;svg class=&#34;anchor-symbol&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; height=&#34;26&#34; width=&#34;26&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 22 22&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M0 0h24v24H0z&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M3.9 12c0-1.71 1.39-3.1 3.1-3.1h4V7H7c-2.76.0-5 2.24-5 5s2.24 5 5 5h4v-1.9H7c-1.71.0-3.1-1.39-3.1-3.1zM8 13h8v-2H8v2zm9-6h-4v1.9h4c1.71.0 3.1 1.39 3.1 3.1s-1.39 3.1-3.1 3.1h-4V17h4c2.76.0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5z&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collaborative engagement with members is crucial to sustained membership in professional associations. It also empowers members to connect, grow, and build relationships across large special interest groups (SIGs) within a widely networked organization. Disengagement, social disconnectedness, and lack of belonging among members are challenges that professional associations deal with at an increasing pace. The ASIS&amp;amp;T SIG-International Information Issues (SIG-III) has over 600 members. One of the challenges of having such a large member base is maintaining engagement and finding ways to connect with an international community of academics and information professionals. Engaging with geographically scattered and culturally diverse members is a demanding situation resulting in weak ties among community members. The pandemic further accentuated the social disruption with the lack of physical gatherings. In this panel presentation, the speakers are officers and members who planned, organized and conducted various successful initiatives. They will share the initiatives they undertook to promote engagement amongst SIG-III members, the best practices for implementing those initiatives, the lessons learned from their experiences, and the outcomes. Other SIGs, Chapters, and professional associations can benefit from the critical lessons shared during this panel.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D/Misinformation on social media and the role of the LIS profession - A South Asian perspective</title>
      <link>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/25/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/25/</guid>
      <description>



&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract
  &lt;a href=&#34;#abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;svg class=&#34;anchor-symbol&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; height=&#34;26&#34; width=&#34;26&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 22 22&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M0 0h24v24H0z&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M3.9 12c0-1.71 1.39-3.1 3.1-3.1h4V7H7c-2.76.0-5 2.24-5 5s2.24 5 5 5h4v-1.9H7c-1.71.0-3.1-1.39-3.1-3.1zM8 13h8v-2H8v2zm9-6h-4v1.9h4c1.71.0 3.1 1.39 3.1 3.1s-1.39 3.1-3.1 3.1h-4V17h4c2.76.0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5z&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The spread of d/misinformation on social media poses serious threats to the social, cultural, political, and economic structures of human societies. This panel is designed to discuss the phenomenon of d/misinformation and fake news on social media, including the motives of its sharing and its impact on society. The panelists will also highlight the role of LIS professionals in educating society to assess the quality of online information before decision-making. Sponsored by the South Asia Chapter and bringing in voices from various South Asian countries and North America, the primary focus of the panel will be on the South Asian perspective in looking at d/misinformation. Synergizing multiple perspectives and firsthand experiences of experts and listeners on the contextual misinformation fact-checking phenomenon while focusing on South Asia, the panel should inform the viewpoints of listeners, while contributing towards the research and practice of information professionals, as well as towards institutional policies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic Modelling and its Application in Libraries: a review of specialized literature</title>
      <link>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/23/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/23/</guid>
      <description>



&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract
  &lt;a href=&#34;#abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;svg class=&#34;anchor-symbol&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; height=&#34;26&#34; width=&#34;26&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 22 22&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M0 0h24v24H0z&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M3.9 12c0-1.71 1.39-3.1 3.1-3.1h4V7H7c-2.76.0-5 2.24-5 5s2.24 5 5 5h4v-1.9H7c-1.71.0-3.1-1.39-3.1-3.1zM8 13h8v-2H8v2zm9-6h-4v1.9h4c1.71.0 3.1 1.39 3.1 3.1s-1.39 3.1-3.1 3.1h-4V17h4c2.76.0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5z&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Text mining application is one of the most trending and highly researched areas in social sciences. Todate, library professionals’ knowledge of text mining tools and practice is mainly limited, resultantly,the library community poorly understands the full range of issues related to text mining. This articleprovides information on applying a text mining approach called topic modelling in the library andinformation science domain. Topic modelling is a text mining approach that determines a generativemodel for documents. This article maps how topic modelling can be used in libraries through variousdatabases during 2009–22 period. It was found that the gap between information users and librarianscan be bridged by text mining training. The study concludes that librarians must develop text miningskills to meet their patrons’ needs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>


