<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks on Manika Lamba</title>
    <link>https://manika-lamba.github.io/talk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Talks on Manika Lamba</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 19:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://manika-lamba.github.io/talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>3rd ASIS&amp;T SIG-III Café Meet</title>
      <link>https://manika-lamba.github.io/talk/2022-05-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manika-lamba.github.io/talk/2022-05-31/</guid>
      <description>&lt;script src=&#34;https://manika-lamba.github.io/talk/2022-05-31/index_files/fitvids/fitvids.min.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;




&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description
  &lt;a href=&#34;#description&#34;&gt;&lt;svg class=&#34;anchor-symbol&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; height=&#34;26&#34; width=&#34;26&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 22 22&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M0 0h24v24H0z&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M3.9 12c0-1.71 1.39-3.1 3.1-3.1h4V7H7c-2.76.0-5 2.24-5 5s2.24 5 5 5h4v-1.9H7c-1.71.0-3.1-1.39-3.1-3.1zM8 13h8v-2H8v2zm9-6h-4v1.9h4c1.71.0 3.1 1.39 3.1 3.1s-1.39 3.1-3.1 3.1h-4V17h4c2.76.0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5z&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s summertime and SIG-III is back again with the 3rd Café International Meet. The theme for the upcoming meet is &amp;ldquo;IT&amp;rsquo;S SUMMER, LET&amp;rsquo;S CONNECT!!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We invite you to come by and share your current interests, pursuit of new skills &amp;amp; hobbies, books/articles you plan to read or are reading, projects you are working on, conferences attended or planning to attend&amp;hellip;anything that you would like to share or talk about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ALL INFORMAL CONVERSATIONS ARE WELCOME!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save the date: 31st May 2022
Time: 7:00 pm IST / 9:30 am EST (Timezone Converter:https://dateful.com/time-zone-converter)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1J4XPy44G1PoTGjkOMzsLofRvQCYBjuhm/preview&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organizers: Manika Lamba, Bhakti Gala, Vanessa Reyes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic Modeling with R</title>
      <link>https://manika-lamba.github.io/talk/2022-04-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 12:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manika-lamba.github.io/talk/2022-04-27/</guid>
      <description>&lt;script src=&#34;https://manika-lamba.github.io/talk/2022-04-27/index_files/fitvids/fitvids.min.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1XlrFCIYkMumhA-W2p0TZiWQWmLRNa-06/preview&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2nd ASIS&amp;T SIG-III Café Meet</title>
      <link>https://manika-lamba.github.io/talk/2022-03-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manika-lamba.github.io/talk/2022-03-17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;script src=&#34;https://manika-lamba.github.io/talk/2022-03-17/index_files/fitvids/fitvids.min.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;




&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description
  &lt;a href=&#34;#description&#34;&gt;&lt;svg class=&#34;anchor-symbol&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; height=&#34;26&#34; width=&#34;26&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 22 22&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M0 0h24v24H0z&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M3.9 12c0-1.71 1.39-3.1 3.1-3.1h4V7H7c-2.76.0-5 2.24-5 5s2.24 5 5 5h4v-1.9H7c-1.71.0-3.1-1.39-3.1-3.1zM8 13h8v-2H8v2zm9-6h-4v1.9h4c1.71.0 3.1 1.39 3.1 3.1s-1.39 3.1-3.1 3.1h-4V17h4c2.76.0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5z&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SIG-III is back again with the 2nd Café International Meet. The theme for the upcoming meet is &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s Connect Through Games: Building Your Network in the Digital Era&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With many games planned, we invite everyone to join us for the fun filled moments. Planned exclusively for you, the success of the event relies on your participation in large numbers. The more attendees the more fun we will have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save the date: Thursday, March 17, 2022 at 7:00 PM IST
Join us through Zoom using the link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://tinyurl.com/2p92yanb&#34;&gt;https://tinyurl.com/2p92yanb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to meeting everyone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organizers: Manika Lamba, Bhakti Gala, Vanessa Reyes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health Information Literacy - Content Creation during the COVID Infodemic</title>
      <link>https://manika-lamba.github.io/talk/2022-02-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manika-lamba.github.io/talk/2022-02-05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;script src=&#34;https://manika-lamba.github.io/talk/2022-02-05/index_files/fitvids/fitvids.min.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;




&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description
  &lt;a href=&#34;#description&#34;&gt;&lt;svg class=&#34;anchor-symbol&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; height=&#34;26&#34; width=&#34;26&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 22 22&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M0 0h24v24H0z&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M3.9 12c0-1.71 1.39-3.1 3.1-3.1h4V7H7c-2.76.0-5 2.24-5 5s2.24 5 5 5h4v-1.9H7c-1.71.0-3.1-1.39-3.1-3.1zM8 13h8v-2H8v2zm9-6h-4v1.9h4c1.71.0 3.1 1.39 3.1 3.1s-1.39 3.1-3.1 3.1h-4V17h4c2.76.0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5z&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the third wave of COVID-19 surges on in different parts of the globe, human society is faced with an onslaught of information related to all aspects of COVID-19. The World Health Organization defines an infodemic as “too much information including false or misleading information in digital and physical environments during a disease outbreak.” Accurate health information will play a critical role in this global fight against the pandemic. Lifesaving decisions need to be taken by individuals to questions like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Should I take the vaccine or not?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How seriously should I follow the COVID-19 protocols?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Should I believe all the forwarded content was shared with me?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone is going to take her/his/their decisions based on how convinced they are with the information searched, found, and read by them. In this context, the panel of speakers will share their experiences in creating health-related content. Librarians and information professionals will play a significant role in this health informatics battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Panelists from five different Asian countries will discuss challenges, strategies and training adopted and imparted for creating accurate and authoritative content. We will share the training imparted to create awareness among primary and secondary students to create and share content. This panel will further address the global challenges of creating multilingual content in forms that are easily accessible and understandable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ifla.org/units/sci-tech-libraries/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sponsored by IFLA Science &amp;amp; Technology Libraries Section&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organizers: Manika Lamba, Kara Whatley, IFLA STL Professional Development Sub-Committee&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h1 id=&#34;presenter-biographies&#34;&gt;Presenter Biographies
  &lt;a href=&#34;#presenter-biographies&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Syeda Hina Batool is an Assistant Professor at the Institute of Information Management, University of the Punjab, New Campus, Lahore, Pakistan. She has done her Ph.D. from iSchool, University of Sheffield, UK. Her research interests focus on examining information literacy instruction and related literacies (health, digital, workplace, visual, media, etc.), through a qualitative research lens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Sam Chu is an Associate Professor at the Faculty of Education, The University of Hong Kong (HKU). Dr. Sam has obtained 2 PhDs in Education each in e-Learning from University College London, UK &amp;amp; the second Ph.D. in Library and Information Science from the University of Hong Kong. His research interests are AI literacy, gamified learning &amp;amp; 21st Century Skills, social media in education, digital literacies, school and academic librarianship, Knowledge Management, and Intellectual Capital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Bhakti Gala is an Assistant Professor at the School of Library and Information Science at the Central University of Gujarat, India. She has received her Ph.D. degree in Library and Information Science from the Maharaja Sayajirao University of Baroda, India. She is currently heading a health informatics project on “Dealing with COVID-19 and saving people’s lives in South Asia (SA) areas &amp;amp; beyond – A health informatics promotion project’ funded by the Association of Information Science and Technology (ASIS&amp;amp;T, USA). Her areas of research are Information Literacy, Equitable access to information, Digital Libraries, Metadata and Authority Control, Open Access, and Open Content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Md. Anwarul Islam is an Associate Professor of Information Science &amp;amp; Library Management at the University of Dhaka, Bangladesh. He received his Ph.D. from the School of Knowledge Science, JAIST, Japan. His research areas are Infometrics, Information Literacy, Information seeking behavior, cloud computing in teaching and learning, social media, and Knowledge Management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prasadi Kanchana Jayasekara is working as a Senior Assistant Librarian at the University of Ruhuna, Sri Lanka. She is currently reading her doctoral degree in Information Systems at the Business School, University of Auckland, New Zealand. She received her B.Sc. degree in Agriculture from the Faculty of Agriculture, University of Ruhuna, Sri Lanka, and a Master’s degree in Library and Information Science from the National Institute of Library and Information Science, University of Colombo, Sri Lanka. Her research interests include social media – information behavior, altmetrics, and information literacy.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h1 id=&#34;moderator-biography&#34;&gt;Moderator Biography
  &lt;a href=&#34;#moderator-biography&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Debal Chandra Kar is serving as University Librarian at Galgotias University. Previously he worked at Dr. B. R. Ambedkar University Delhi (2011-2021) as University Librarian, The Energy and Resources Institute (TERI), New Delhi as a Fellow and other different positions (1986-2011) including TERI University as University Librarian (2001-2005). He has been privileged to receive a number of awards recognizing his achievements like SLA Fellow (USA), SLA Bonnie Hilditch International Science &amp;amp; Technology Librarian Award 2008, SLA Presidential Citation Award 2008, SLA Proquest Dialog Member Achievement Award 2011, SLA-S&amp;amp;T Librarian Achievement Award 2011, and SLA-PAM Special International Librarian award 2018, from the Special Libraries Association USA. He was the founder-editor of World Digital Libraries – an International journal (2008-2012). He served as president of SLA Asian Community/Chapter in 2008, 2017, and 2021. He is Vice-Chair of the IFLA Regional Division Committee – Asia and Oceania 2021-2023 and IFLA Social Science Libraries Section Standing Committee 2021-2025 member.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1F7NzDmdQflcjvKueAqW1a5YSfE0X_4R-/preview&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1st ASIS&amp;T SIG-III Café Meet</title>
      <link>https://manika-lamba.github.io/talk/2022-01-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manika-lamba.github.io/talk/2022-01-20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;script src=&#34;https://manika-lamba.github.io/talk/2022-01-20/index_files/fitvids/fitvids.min.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;




&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description
  &lt;a href=&#34;#description&#34;&gt;&lt;svg class=&#34;anchor-symbol&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; height=&#34;26&#34; width=&#34;26&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 22 22&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M0 0h24v24H0z&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M3.9 12c0-1.71 1.39-3.1 3.1-3.1h4V7H7c-2.76.0-5 2.24-5 5s2.24 5 5 5h4v-1.9H7c-1.71.0-3.1-1.39-3.1-3.1zM8 13h8v-2H8v2zm9-6h-4v1.9h4c1.71.0 3.1 1.39 3.1 3.1s-1.39 3.1-3.1 3.1h-4V17h4c2.76.0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5z&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are you looking for an opportunity to vent out your stress?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Would you like to seek professional guidance from our community members?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How about a space for having a relaxing and friendly conversation?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Would you like an opportunity to seek guidance to help you out through a difficult situation?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SIG-III International Café has organized its first informal meeting to provide these opportunities to all its members. We invite all practitioners, faculty and students to join us with your favorite drink on 20th January 2022 at 7:30 pm IST (Timezone Converter:https://dateful.com/time-zone-converter)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organizers: Manika Lamba, Bhakti Gala, Vanessa Reyes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/14pfsQzYkUlNmBJV3adGITp5RP-XA76H9/preview&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acceleration of Health Information Literacy</title>
      <link>https://manika-lamba.github.io/talk/2021-12-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manika-lamba.github.io/talk/2021-12-18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;script src=&#34;https://manika-lamba.github.io/talk/2021-12-18/index_files/fitvids/fitvids.min.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;




&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description
  &lt;a href=&#34;#description&#34;&gt;&lt;svg class=&#34;anchor-symbol&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; height=&#34;26&#34; width=&#34;26&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 22 22&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M0 0h24v24H0z&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M3.9 12c0-1.71 1.39-3.1 3.1-3.1h4V7H7c-2.76.0-5 2.24-5 5s2.24 5 5 5h4v-1.9H7c-1.71.0-3.1-1.39-3.1-3.1zM8 13h8v-2H8v2zm9-6h-4v1.9h4c1.71.0 3.1 1.39 3.1 3.1s-1.39 3.1-3.1 3.1h-4V17h4c2.76.0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5z&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The South Asia Chapter is pleased to announce the webinar on &amp;ldquo;Acceleration of Health Information Literacy: Preparing Multi-Lingual COVID-19 Contents for South Asia Region” to be jointly organized with the Department of Information Science and Library Management, University of Dhaka. The webinar was held on 18th December 2021 at 5:30 PM IST via Zoom.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h2 id=&#34;presenters&#34;&gt;Presenters
  &lt;a href=&#34;#presenters&#34;&gt;&lt;svg class=&#34;anchor-symbol&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; height=&#34;26&#34; width=&#34;26&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 22 22&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M0 0h24v24H0z&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M3.9 12c0-1.71 1.39-3.1 3.1-3.1h4V7H7c-2.76.0-5 2.24-5 5s2.24 5 5 5h4v-1.9H7c-1.71.0-3.1-1.39-3.1-3.1zM8 13h8v-2H8v2zm9-6h-4v1.9h4c1.71.0 3.1 1.39 3.1 3.1s-1.39 3.1-3.1 3.1h-4V17h4c2.76.0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5z&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Professor Dr. Md. Akhtaruzzaman, Honourable Vice-Chancellor, University of Dhaka graced the occasion as Chief Guest. Professor Dr. Md. Nasiruddin Munshi, Department of Information Science and Library Management &amp;amp; Librarian (In-Charge) of Dhaka University Library presented as Special Guest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The keynote paper was presented by Dr. Samuel K. W. Chu, Associate Professor, Faculty of Education, University of Hong Kong. Professor Dr. S. M. Zabed Ahmed, Department of Information Science and Library Management, University of Dhaka lead the discussion with Professor Dr. Md. Shiful Islam (Chairman of ISLM Department, DU), Dr. Dilara Begum (Chairman, Department of Information Studies and Library Management, East-West University), A.K.M. Eamin Ali Akanda (Chairman of ISLM Department, RU) and Razina Alam (Head of Library), Bangladesh Shishu Academy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1ddlK8E9SGqM0Q23Z_xTI9uPC6tLMxRBN/preview&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Carpentries &amp; Author Carpentry</title>
      <link>https://manika-lamba.github.io/talk/2021-12-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 04:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manika-lamba.github.io/talk/2021-12-15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;script src=&#34;https://manika-lamba.github.io/talk/2021-12-15/index_files/fitvids/fitvids.min.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;




&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description
  &lt;a href=&#34;#description&#34;&gt;&lt;svg class=&#34;anchor-symbol&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; height=&#34;26&#34; width=&#34;26&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 22 22&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M0 0h24v24H0z&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M3.9 12c0-1.71 1.39-3.1 3.1-3.1h4V7H7c-2.76.0-5 2.24-5 5s2.24 5 5 5h4v-1.9H7c-1.71.0-3.1-1.39-3.1-3.1zM8 13h8v-2H8v2zm9-6h-4v1.9h4c1.71.0 3.1 1.39 3.1 3.1s-1.39 3.1-3.1 3.1h-4V17h4c2.76.0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5z&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This webinar will provide a brief introduction to The Carpentries instructional philosophy of researcher-to-researcher computational training. We’ll then discuss Author Carpentry, an independent set of modules that can be integrated into a Carpentries Workshops or taught as an independent curriculum. They cover topics not traditionally included in a Carpentry Workshop, such as open authorship, writing in standard formats like Markdown, creating a reproducible and interactive report in RStudio, digital object identifiers, and ORCID IDs. We’ll discuss the future of Author Carpentry and ways you can be involved in the development of this open curriculum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ifla.org/units/sci-tech-libraries/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sponsored by IFLA Science &amp;amp; Technology Libraries Section&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organizers: Manika Lamba (Chair) and Kara Whatley, IFLA STL Professional Development Sub-Committee&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h2 id=&#34;presenters-biography&#34;&gt;Presenters Biography
  &lt;a href=&#34;#presenters-biography&#34;&gt;&lt;svg class=&#34;anchor-symbol&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; height=&#34;26&#34; width=&#34;26&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 22 22&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M0 0h24v24H0z&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M3.9 12c0-1.71 1.39-3.1 3.1-3.1h4V7H7c-2.76.0-5 2.24-5 5s2.24 5 5 5h4v-1.9H7c-1.71.0-3.1-1.39-3.1-3.1zM8 13h8v-2H8v2zm9-6h-4v1.9h4c1.71.0 3.1 1.39 3.1 3.1s-1.39 3.1-3.1 3.1h-4V17h4c2.76.0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5z&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tom Morrell is the Research Data Specialist at Caltech Library. He manages the CaltechDATA institutional repository for research data and software, and helps Caltech researchers share their results with the world. Tom has been a certified Carpentry instructor for five years and taught numerous Software and Data Carpentry Workshops. Tom also helped create the Author Carpentry curriculum and has taught Author Carpentry lessons at Caltech and the FORCE 11 Scholarly Communication Institute (FSCI). Tom has a background in computational chemistry and brings a researcher-focused perspective to his work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/11P71cRQs3HgZsKQuPzxOOGAyIlWuMIKD/preview&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5th Library Technology Conclave (LTC2021)​​</title>
      <link>https://manika-lamba.github.io/talk/2021-01-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manika-lamba.github.io/talk/2021-01-30/</guid>
      <description>&lt;script src=&#34;https://manika-lamba.github.io/talk/2021-01-30/index_files/fitvids/fitvids.min.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;




&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description
  &lt;a href=&#34;#description&#34;&gt;&lt;svg class=&#34;anchor-symbol&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; height=&#34;26&#34; width=&#34;26&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 22 22&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M0 0h24v24H0z&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M3.9 12c0-1.71 1.39-3.1 3.1-3.1h4V7H7c-2.76.0-5 2.24-5 5s2.24 5 5 5h4v-1.9H7c-1.71.0-3.1-1.39-3.1-3.1zM8 13h8v-2H8v2zm9-6h-4v1.9h4c1.71.0 3.1 1.39 3.1 3.1s-1.39 3.1-3.1 3.1h-4V17h4c2.76.0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5z&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was invited as a discussant to the “Social Media Research” session at 5th Library Technology Conclave (LTC2021)​​. This section consists of two short videos where you will get answers to the two questions I asked during the session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question 1 : How to overcome major biases in social media research data?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://youtube.com/embed/alnXjR_-OB8&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question 2 : Is there any ethical framework for social media research?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://youtube.com/embed/rYmGZCitCOk&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>


