<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Manika Lamba</title>
    <link>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Manika Lamba</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>South Asia Chapter Newsletter 2022 Vol. 1 Issue 1</title>
      <link>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/19/</guid>
      <description>



&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract
  &lt;a href=&#34;#abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;svg class=&#34;anchor-symbol&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; height=&#34;26&#34; width=&#34;26&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 22 22&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M0 0h24v24H0z&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M3.9 12c0-1.71 1.39-3.1 3.1-3.1h4V7H7c-2.76.0-5 2.24-5 5s2.24 5 5 5h4v-1.9H7c-1.71.0-3.1-1.39-3.1-3.1zM8 13h8v-2H8v2zm9-6h-4v1.9h4c1.71.0 3.1 1.39 3.1 3.1s-1.39 3.1-3.1 3.1h-4V17h4c2.76.0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5z&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second newsletter of the South Asia Chapter of the Association for Information Science and Technology (ASIS&amp;amp;T-SA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://cdn.flipsnack.com/widget/v2/widget.html?hash=tjlv80fcjl&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; seamless=&#34;seamless&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameBorder=&#34;0&#34; allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; 
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barriers to Scholarly Publishing Among Library and Information Science Researchers: International Perspectives</title>
      <link>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract
  &lt;a href=&#34;#abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;svg class=&#34;anchor-symbol&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; height=&#34;26&#34; width=&#34;26&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 22 22&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M0 0h24v24H0z&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M3.9 12c0-1.71 1.39-3.1 3.1-3.1h4V7H7c-2.76.0-5 2.24-5 5s2.24 5 5 5h4v-1.9H7c-1.71.0-3.1-1.39-3.1-3.1zM8 13h8v-2H8v2zm9-6h-4v1.9h4c1.71.0 3.1 1.39 3.1 3.1s-1.39 3.1-3.1 3.1h-4V17h4c2.76.0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5z&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 21 authors of this study, 19 of whom are non-native English speakers, reflect on the barriers to publishing academic journal articles in top international journals. Each author responded to the same set of questions pertaining to educational (PhD) opportunities for emerging scholars, financial conditions for researchers, and challenges in publishing their work. Limited English language skills, lack of research funding, and different research topics were identified as the most significant barriers to publish in the journals. Recruiting volunteers or using electronic translations for accepted articles for journals, reducing software and subscription to academic journals costs, expanding journal scope, and providing guidance and collaboration across borders are possible measures to reduce the negative impact of the barriers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>South Asia Chapter Newsletter 2021 Vol. 1 Issue 1</title>
      <link>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/17/</guid>
      <description>



&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract
  &lt;a href=&#34;#abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;svg class=&#34;anchor-symbol&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; height=&#34;26&#34; width=&#34;26&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 22 22&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M0 0h24v24H0z&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M3.9 12c0-1.71 1.39-3.1 3.1-3.1h4V7H7c-2.76.0-5 2.24-5 5s2.24 5 5 5h4v-1.9H7c-1.71.0-3.1-1.39-3.1-3.1zM8 13h8v-2H8v2zm9-6h-4v1.9h4c1.71.0 3.1 1.39 3.1 3.1s-1.39 3.1-3.1 3.1h-4V17h4c2.76.0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5z&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first newsletter of the South Asia Chapter of the Association for Information Science and Technology (ASIS&amp;amp;T-SA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://cdn.flipsnack.com/widget/v2/widget.html?hash=hmq1ss31ci&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; seamless=&#34;seamless&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameBorder=&#34;0&#34; allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The changing roles of librarians: Managing emerging technologies in libraries</title>
      <link>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract
  &lt;a href=&#34;#abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;svg class=&#34;anchor-symbol&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; height=&#34;26&#34; width=&#34;26&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 22 22&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M0 0h24v24H0z&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M3.9 12c0-1.71 1.39-3.1 3.1-3.1h4V7H7c-2.76.0-5 2.24-5 5s2.24 5 5 5h4v-1.9H7c-1.71.0-3.1-1.39-3.1-3.1zM8 13h8v-2H8v2zm9-6h-4v1.9h4c1.71.0 3.1 1.39 3.1 3.1s-1.39 3.1-3.1 3.1h-4V17h4c2.76.0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5z&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This chapter presents an overview of the changing roles of an academic liaison librarian who is also popularly known as liaison librarian or subject librarian or subject specialist. The major activities which are being performed by a liaison librarian have been categorized. Further, the skills and competencies required by a liaison librarian to perform the activities have been summarized.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Evaluation of Computer Science Departments: A Cohort Study of Indian Central Universities</title>
      <link>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/15/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract
  &lt;a href=&#34;#abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;svg class=&#34;anchor-symbol&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; height=&#34;26&#34; width=&#34;26&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 22 22&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M0 0h24v24H0z&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M3.9 12c0-1.71 1.39-3.1 3.1-3.1h4V7H7c-2.76.0-5 2.24-5 5s2.24 5 5 5h4v-1.9H7c-1.71.0-3.1-1.39-3.1-3.1zM8 13h8v-2H8v2zm9-6h-4v1.9h4c1.71.0 3.1 1.39 3.1 3.1s-1.39 3.1-3.1 3.1h-4V17h4c2.76.0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5z&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;: Social interaction applications and reference tools are actively used by researchers to share and manage their research publications. Thus, this paper aims to determine the scholarly impact of selected Indian central universities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design/methodology/approach&lt;/strong&gt;: This study analyzed 669 articles having both Dimensions citations and Altmetric attention scores published by 35 Indian central universities for 4 subfields of Computer Science using Altmetric Explorer. This paper determined each university’s contribution in the studied subfields of Computer Science and the correlation among Altmetric attention score (aggregated and individual), Dimensions citation, and Mendeley readership counts for all 669 articles and stratified percentile sets of top 25%, and top 50% of the overall number of articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Findings&lt;/strong&gt;: The findings showed that Jawaharlal Nehru University had the maximum Altmetric attention score, Banaras Hindu University received the maximum Dimensions citation, and University of Hyderabad (UoH) received the maximum number of Mendeley readers. Each central university was examined individually and then ranked based on their median values of Dimensions citations and Altmetric attention scores. Further, Twitter had the maximum Altmetric coverage, followed by Google+, Patent and Facebook for the retrieved articles. A significant strong positive correlation was observed between the Dimensions citation and Mendeley readership counts for all the three categories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Research limitations/implications&lt;/strong&gt;: Both Altmetric attention scores and Dimensions citations can help funding agencies to assess and evaluate the research productivity of these universities, thus, making important decisions such as increasing, decreasing, re-distributing their funds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Originality/value&lt;/strong&gt;: The current body of research is focused mostly on relationships between citations and individual Altmetric indicators predominantly. For most of the studies, the citations were retrieved from Scopus, Web of Science or Google Scholar database. It was observed that by far, no study had examined the relationship between citations retrieved from Dimensions database, Altmetrics scores (both aggregated and individual) and Mendeley readership counts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bibliometric Analysis of papers published during 1992 to 2019 in DESIDOC Journal of Library and Information Technology</title>
      <link>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract
  &lt;a href=&#34;#abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;svg class=&#34;anchor-symbol&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; height=&#34;26&#34; width=&#34;26&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 22 22&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M0 0h24v24H0z&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M3.9 12c0-1.71 1.39-3.1 3.1-3.1h4V7H7c-2.76.0-5 2.24-5 5s2.24 5 5 5h4v-1.9H7c-1.71.0-3.1-1.39-3.1-3.1zM8 13h8v-2H8v2zm9-6h-4v1.9h4c1.71.0 3.1 1.39 3.1 3.1s-1.39 3.1-3.1 3.1h-4V17h4c2.76.0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5z&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study analyses papers published in DESIDOC Journal of Library and Information Technology (DJLIT) using bibliometric techniques for the period of 1992-2019 (28 years) and citations received by these papers until 20th March 2020as reflected by Google Scholar. The study examined the pattern of growth, geographical distribution of the articles; identified the prolific authors &amp;amp; institutions, and their output; and the pattern of citations of the papers and identified most cited authors. The findings indicate that the highest number of articles was published during 2012-2015 followed by 2016-2019. The distribution of output by countries indicates that 39 countries contributed 1,698 articles, including India. Indian authors published the highest percentage (86.1 %) of articles followed by USA and had the highest value of CPP and RCI. Authors affiliated to different institutions of Delhi contributed the most (30.7 %) followed by Karnataka (13.1 %) and Maharashtra (10.5 %). Among the institutions, DRDO-DESIDOC and CSIR-NISTADS topped the list. Among the 26 most prolific authors, B.M. Gupta (CSIR-NISTADS) published the maximum number of articles. However, B.R. Babu (University of Madras, Chennai) had the highest value of CPP and RCI. During the studied period, 1,698 papers obtained 15,538 citations, of which 248 (14.6 %) articles did not receive any citation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research productivity of health care policy faculty: a cohort study of Harvard Medical School</title>
      <link>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract
  &lt;a href=&#34;#abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;svg class=&#34;anchor-symbol&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; height=&#34;26&#34; width=&#34;26&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 22 22&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M0 0h24v24H0z&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M3.9 12c0-1.71 1.39-3.1 3.1-3.1h4V7H7c-2.76.0-5 2.24-5 5s2.24 5 5 5h4v-1.9H7c-1.71.0-3.1-1.39-3.1-3.1zM8 13h8v-2H8v2zm9-6h-4v1.9h4c1.71.0 3.1 1.39 3.1 3.1s-1.39 3.1-3.1 3.1h-4V17h4c2.76.0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5z&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In today’s publish or perish environment, the scholarly impact of a research article holds great importance. The present study examined 2343 articles having both altmetric attention scores and citations published by 22 core health care policy faculty members at Harvard Medical School. Web of Science was used to retrieve the citations, whereas Altmetric Explorer was used to determine the altmetric attention score. The evaluation metrics in this study were focused on article-level information to determine each faculty member’s contribution to the health care policy department collected in November 2018. This paper further determined the predictive capability of altmetric attention score for the increase of citations from November 2018 to January 2020. The findings showed J. Michael McWilliams (Professor); Anupam B. Jena (Associate Professor); and Zirui Song (Assistant Professor) were the faculty members with highest altmetric attention score while Ronald C. Kessler (Professor); Nicole Maestas (Associate Professor); and Zirui Song (Assistant Professor) were the faculty members with the highest citation value. The lowest percentage (5.84%) of articles without any citations were published by the professors, whereas the lowest percentage (4.84%) of articles without any social media mention were published by the assistant professors. The health care faculty had the highest percentage of Mendeley readerships followed by tweets, news, and blogs mention in comparison to a meager percentage of policy-related documents mention for their retrieved articles. A significant strong positive correlation (rR &amp;gt; 0.4) was observed between the aggregated ranked altmetric attention scores and ranked citation/increased citation values for all the faculty members. This study can be extended to determine the research productivity of any department, discipline, or group of faculty members.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping of ETDs in ProQuest dissertations and theses (PQDT) global database (2014-2018)</title>
      <link>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://publicacoes.bad.pt/revistas/index.php/cadernos/article/view/2034/pdf&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; seamless=&#34;seamless&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameBorder=&#34;0&#34; allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;




&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract
  &lt;a href=&#34;#abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;svg class=&#34;anchor-symbol&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; height=&#34;26&#34; width=&#34;26&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 22 22&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M0 0h24v24H0z&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M3.9 12c0-1.71 1.39-3.1 3.1-3.1h4V7H7c-2.76.0-5 2.24-5 5s2.24 5 5 5h4v-1.9H7c-1.71.0-3.1-1.39-3.1-3.1zM8 13h8v-2H8v2zm9-6h-4v1.9h4c1.71.0 3.1 1.39 3.1 3.1s-1.39 3.1-3.1 3.1h-4V17h4c2.76.0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5z&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The information explosion in the form of ETDs poses the challenge of management and extraction of appropriate knowledge for decision making by information practitioners. This study presents a solution to the problem by applying topic mining and prediction modeling to 441 full-text ETDs extracted from the PQDT Global database during 2014-2018 in the field of library science using the RapidMiner platform. This study was divided into three phases. In the first phase, metadata analysis of the ETDs retrieved from the database was performed to identify the association of various entities such as universities, departments, types of degrees, and geographical areas with the ETDs. In the second phase, 8 core topics namely children literature; academic library; information retrieval; archival science; user study; digital library; library leadership; and digital communication were determined using latent dirichlet allocation (LDA) and each ETD was then annotated with the modeled topic. Lastly, a prediction model using the Support Vector Machine (SVM) was created to classify the untagged ETDs going to be submitted in the database under the 8 modeled topics (a to h).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Analysis of ETDs in ProQuest Dissertations and Theses (PQDT) Global (2016-2018)</title>
      <link>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract
  &lt;a href=&#34;#abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;svg class=&#34;anchor-symbol&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; height=&#34;26&#34; width=&#34;26&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 22 22&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M0 0h24v24H0z&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M3.9 12c0-1.71 1.39-3.1 3.1-3.1h4V7H7c-2.76.0-5 2.24-5 5s2.24 5 5 5h4v-1.9H7c-1.71.0-3.1-1.39-3.1-3.1zM8 13h8v-2H8v2zm9-6h-4v1.9h4c1.71.0 3.1 1.39 3.1 3.1s-1.39 3.1-3.1 3.1h-4V17h4c2.76.0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5z&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The information explosion in the form of ETDs poses the challenge of management and extraction of appropriate knowledge for decision making. Thus, the present study forwards a solution to the above problem by applying topic mining and prediction modeling tools to full-text 263 ETDs submitted to the PQDT Global database during 2016-18 in the field of library science. This study was divided into two phases. The first phase determined the core topics from the ETDs using Topic-Modeling-Tool (TMT), which was based on latent dirichlet allocation (LDA), whereas the second phase employed prediction analysis using RapidMiner platform to annotate the future research articles on the basis of the modeled topics. The core topics (tags) for the studied period were found to be book history, school librarian, public library, communicative ecology, and informatics followed by text network and trend analysis on the high probability co-occurred words. Lastly, a prediction model using the Support Vector Machine (SVM) classifier was created in order to accurately predict the placement of future ETDs going to be submitted to PQDT Global under the five modeled topics (a to e). The tested dataset against the trained data set for the predictive performed perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metadata Tagging and Prediction Modeling: Case Study of DESIDOC Journal of Library and Information Technology (2008–17)</title>
      <link>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://c2744e85-8ae9-4a90-817b-76bb75cd410b.filesusr.com/ugd/ff38f5_e0ce908404a84502be3423a295797448.pdf&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; seamless=&#34;seamless&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameBorder=&#34;0&#34; allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;




&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract
  &lt;a href=&#34;#abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;svg class=&#34;anchor-symbol&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; height=&#34;26&#34; width=&#34;26&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 22 22&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M0 0h24v24H0z&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M3.9 12c0-1.71 1.39-3.1 3.1-3.1h4V7H7c-2.76.0-5 2.24-5 5s2.24 5 5 5h4v-1.9H7c-1.71.0-3.1-1.39-3.1-3.1zM8 13h8v-2H8v2zm9-6h-4v1.9h4c1.71.0 3.1 1.39 3.1 3.1s-1.39 3.1-3.1 3.1h-4V17h4c2.76.0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5z&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The present paper describes the importance and usage of metadata tagging and prediction modeling tools for researchers and librarians. 387 articles were downloaded from DESIDOC Journal of Library and Information Technology (DJLIT) for the period 2008-17 excluding guest editorials and special editions. This study was divided into two phases. The first phase determined the core Topics from the research articles using Topic-Modeling-Tool (TMT) , which was based on latent Dirichlet allocation (LDA), whereas the second phase employed prediction analysis using RapidMiner toolbox to annotate the future research articles on the basis of the modeled topics. The core topics (tags) were found to be digital libraries, information literacy, scientometrics, open access, and library resources for the studied period. This study further annotated the scientific articles according to the modeled topics to provide a better searching experience to its users. Sugimoto, Li, Russell, et al. (2011), Figuerola, Marco, and Pinto (2017), and Lamba and Madhusudhan (2018) have performed studies similar to the present paper but with major modifications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping of topics in DESIDOC Journal of Library and Information Technology, India: a study</title>
      <link>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract
  &lt;a href=&#34;#abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;svg class=&#34;anchor-symbol&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; height=&#34;26&#34; width=&#34;26&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 22 22&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M0 0h24v24H0z&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M3.9 12c0-1.71 1.39-3.1 3.1-3.1h4V7H7c-2.76.0-5 2.24-5 5s2.24 5 5 5h4v-1.9H7c-1.71.0-3.1-1.39-3.1-3.1zM8 13h8v-2H8v2zm9-6h-4v1.9h4c1.71.0 3.1 1.39 3.1 3.1s-1.39 3.1-3.1 3.1h-4V17h4c2.76.0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5z&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study analyzed 928 full-text research articles retrieved from DESIDOC Journal of Library and Information Technology for the period of 1981–2018 using Latent Dirichlet Allocation. The study further tagged the articles with the modeled topics. 50 core topics were identified throughout the period of 38 years whereas only 26 topics were unique in nature. Bibliometrics, ICT, information retrieval, and user studies were highly researched areas in India for the epoch. Further, Spain and Taiwan showed common research trends and areas as India whereas India has quite distinct research interests from America and China. Therefore, researchers in Library and Information Science in India should pay more attention to the topics which are under-researched. Further, it was found that there were some unique sub-fields to Indian Library and Information Science research, such as open access; online exhibition; virtual libraries; multimedia libraries; open source software; library automation; and library management system. With the passage of time topics evolve over time, new topics emerge, and old ones become obsolete. Topic modeling not only helps the researcher to determine the trending themes or related fields with respect to their field of interest but also helps them to identify new concepts and fields over time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Author-Topic Modeling of DESIDOC Journal of Library and Information Technology (2008-2017), India</title>
      <link>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://digitalcommons.unl.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=5983&amp;context=libphilprac&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; seamless=&#34;seamless&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameBorder=&#34;0&#34; allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;




&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract
  &lt;a href=&#34;#abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;svg class=&#34;anchor-symbol&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; height=&#34;26&#34; width=&#34;26&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 22 22&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M0 0h24v24H0z&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M3.9 12c0-1.71 1.39-3.1 3.1-3.1h4V7H7c-2.76.0-5 2.24-5 5s2.24 5 5 5h4v-1.9H7c-1.71.0-3.1-1.39-3.1-3.1zM8 13h8v-2H8v2zm9-6h-4v1.9h4c1.71.0 3.1 1.39 3.1 3.1s-1.39 3.1-3.1 3.1h-4V17h4c2.76.0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5z&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study presents a method to analyze textual data and applying it to the field of Library and Information Science. This paper subsumes a special case of Latent Dirichlet Allocation and Author-Topic models where each article has one unique author and each author has one unique topic. Topic Modeling Toolkit is used to perform the author-topic modeling. The study further which considers topics and their changes over time by taking into account both the word co-occurrence pattern and time. 393 full-text articles were downloaded from DESIDOC Journal of Library and Information Technology and were analyzed accordingly. 16 core topics have been identified throughout the period of ten years. These core topics can be considered as the core area of research in the journal from 2008 to 2017. This paper further identifies top five authors associated with the representative articles for each studied year. These authors can be treated as the subject-experts for the modeled topics as indicated. The results of the study can serve as a platform to determine the research trend; core areas of research; and the subject-experts related to those core areas in the field the Library and Information Science in India.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Paradigm in Library 2.0 Sentiment Analysis of Twitter</title>
      <link>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract
  &lt;a href=&#34;#abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;svg class=&#34;anchor-symbol&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; height=&#34;26&#34; width=&#34;26&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 22 22&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M0 0h24v24H0z&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M3.9 12c0-1.71 1.39-3.1 3.1-3.1h4V7H7c-2.76.0-5 2.24-5 5s2.24 5 5 5h4v-1.9H7c-1.71.0-3.1-1.39-3.1-3.1zM8 13h8v-2H8v2zm9-6h-4v1.9h4c1.71.0 3.1 1.39 3.1 3.1s-1.39 3.1-3.1 3.1h-4V17h4c2.76.0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5z&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This chapter presents a conceptual framework of Sentiment Analysis and its application in the field of Library and Information Science. Sentiment Analysis of social media platforms will help the policy makers, researchers, and market analysts to understand the views and opinions generated by the public on an international platform related to the various facets of libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marketing of academic health libraries 2.0: a case study</title>
      <link>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract
  &lt;a href=&#34;#abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;svg class=&#34;anchor-symbol&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; height=&#34;26&#34; width=&#34;26&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 22 22&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M0 0h24v24H0z&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M3.9 12c0-1.71 1.39-3.1 3.1-3.1h4V7H7c-2.76.0-5 2.24-5 5s2.24 5 5 5h4v-1.9H7c-1.71.0-3.1-1.39-3.1-3.1zM8 13h8v-2H8v2zm9-6h-4v1.9h4c1.71.0 3.1 1.39 3.1 3.1s-1.39 3.1-3.1 3.1h-4V17h4c2.76.0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5z&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advent of Web 2.0 in libraries persuades the librarians to adopt new ways to communicate, determine, and satisfy the needs of the users. The paper aims to discuss this issue. A 30-question questionnaire was given to 30 undergraduate medical students of Vardhman Mahavir Medical College and a 10-question questionnaire was given to the librarian, to find out the marketing and promotional strategies employed by the library; determine the awareness and satisfaction level of the users; prepare library profile, customer profile and market profile; and perform SWOT analysis. User responses were coded and processed using GNU PSPP software. From the library profile of Vardhman Mahavir Medical College library, it can be concluded that the library has the potential to offer better services and products to its users. From the customer profile of Vardhman Mahavir Medical College library, it is concluded that the most of its users are young male undergraduate students who use the library more on weekly basis. From the market profile of Vardhman Mahavir Medical College library, it is concluded that the library has not invested in the marketing and has no promotion strategy or marketing strategy for its products and services. Also, the library has only one digital promotional activity. From the SWOT analysis of Vardhman Mahavir Medical College library, it is concluded that the library does not use any of the social platforms to market its products and services. Most of the users are unaware of the services and products offered by the library. There are many opportunities for the library to work upon and improve the quality of products and services being offered to its users. The major limitation of the present study is its small sample size. It is very difficult to conduct surveys in health libraries because of the busy schedule of the undergraduate medical students and their reluctance to fill out lengthy questionnaires. However, this small sample size only made it possible to conduct the SWOT analysis on the basis of the users’ survey successfully. Further, the small sample size helped to take into account all the opportunities stated by the users which would not have been possible if a larger sample size was taken. This study is one of a kind which provides an overview of marketing research of an academic health library of New Delhi (India) with a special focus on library profile, market profile, customer profile and SWOT analysis. It addresses the gaps in the literature by studying marketing in the context of academic health libraries in the digital environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Marketing of University College of Medical Sciences Library, University of Delhi: a Study</title>
      <link>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract
  &lt;a href=&#34;#abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;svg class=&#34;anchor-symbol&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; height=&#34;26&#34; width=&#34;26&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 22 22&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M0 0h24v24H0z&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M3.9 12c0-1.71 1.39-3.1 3.1-3.1h4V7H7c-2.76.0-5 2.24-5 5s2.24 5 5 5h4v-1.9H7c-1.71.0-3.1-1.39-3.1-3.1zM8 13h8v-2H8v2zm9-6h-4v1.9h4c1.71.0 3.1 1.39 3.1 3.1s-1.39 3.1-3.1 3.1h-4V17h4c2.76.0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5z&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advent of Web 2.0 in libraries persuades the librarians to adopt new ways to communicate, determine and satisfy the needs of the users. For this study a questionnaire was given to the medical students of University College of Medical Sciences and another questionnaire was given to the librarian, to find out: the marketing and promotional strategies employed by the library; determine the awareness and satisfaction level of the users; prepare customer profile and market profile, and perform SWOT analysis. The data were coded and processed using GNU PSPP software. The findings of the study show that the library does not use any of the social platforms to market its products and services and most of the users are unaware of the services and products offered by the library. There are many opportunities for the library to work upon and improve the quality of products and services being offered to its users. Digital marketing is the latest marketing trend using web 2.0 tools but is rarely employed by academic health libraries in India.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metadata Tagging of Library and Information Science Theses Shodhganga (2013-2017)</title>
      <link>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/5/</guid>
      <description>



&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract
  &lt;a href=&#34;#abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;svg class=&#34;anchor-symbol&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; height=&#34;26&#34; width=&#34;26&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 22 22&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M0 0h24v24H0z&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M3.9 12c0-1.71 1.39-3.1 3.1-3.1h4V7H7c-2.76.0-5 2.24-5 5s2.24 5 5 5h4v-1.9H7c-1.71.0-3.1-1.39-3.1-3.1zM8 13h8v-2H8v2zm9-6h-4v1.9h4c1.71.0 3.1 1.39 3.1 3.1s-1.39 3.1-3.1 3.1h-4V17h4c2.76.0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5z&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electronic Theses and Dissertations (ETDs) poses the challenge of managing and extraction of appropriate knowledge for decision making. To tackle the same, topic modeling was first applied to Library and Information Science (LIS) theses submitted to Shodhganga (an Indian ETDs digital repository) to determine the five core topics/tags and then the performance of the built model based on those topics/tags were analyzed. Using a Latent Dirichlet Allocation based Topic-Modeling-Toolkit, the five core topics were found to be information literacy, user studies, scientometrics, library resources and library services for the epoch 2013-2017 and consequently all the theses were summarized with the presence of their respective topic proportion for the tags/topics. A Support Vector Machine (Linear) prediction model using RapidMiner toolbox was created and showed 88.78% accuracy with 0.85 kappa value.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Application of sentiment analysis in libraries to provide temporal information service: a case study on various facets of productivity</title>
      <link>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract
  &lt;a href=&#34;#abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;svg class=&#34;anchor-symbol&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; height=&#34;26&#34; width=&#34;26&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 22 22&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M0 0h24v24H0z&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M3.9 12c0-1.71 1.39-3.1 3.1-3.1h4V7H7c-2.76.0-5 2.24-5 5s2.24 5 5 5h4v-1.9H7c-1.71.0-3.1-1.39-3.1-3.1zM8 13h8v-2H8v2zm9-6h-4v1.9h4c1.71.0 3.1 1.39 3.1 3.1s-1.39 3.1-3.1 3.1h-4V17h4c2.76.0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5z&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the advent of social media, people have found new ways through which they can express their views, opinions, and beliefs . This study presents an interdisciplinary nature of research where sentiment analysis is applied to the economics discipline of productivity as an experimental study to introduce new service for libraries’ users. Firstly, data were retrieved from Twitter on 20 different queries related to productivity using RapidMiner platform and then sentiment analysis was performed employing AYLIEN Text Analysis Software. A total of 6416 tweets were mined from Twitter for a period of 13 days. Further, 676 prominent hashtags had been identified where 83 hashtags were found to be associated with a geographical location in the tweets. It was observed that the United Kingdom was the most popular country which was being used as a hashtag on Twitter in relation to various facets of the productivity followed by India, the United States, China, and Nigeria. In regard to polarity, most of the tweets were found to be of neutral polarity and most of the positive tweets had a low percentage value. The information analyzed using this strategy can be repackaged as a consolidated time-based service and can be presented to libraries’ users in different formats. This study not only introduces a nascent way to cater to the information needs of today’s users, but also proposes a new way of conducting marketing in libraries using social media mining and sentiment analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Application of Topic Mining and Prediction Modeling Tools for Library and Information Science Journals</title>
      <link>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract
  &lt;a href=&#34;#abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;svg class=&#34;anchor-symbol&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; height=&#34;26&#34; width=&#34;26&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 22 22&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M0 0h24v24H0z&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M3.9 12c0-1.71 1.39-3.1 3.1-3.1h4V7H7c-2.76.0-5 2.24-5 5s2.24 5 5 5h4v-1.9H7c-1.71.0-3.1-1.39-3.1-3.1zM8 13h8v-2H8v2zm9-6h-4v1.9h4c1.71.0 3.1 1.39 3.1 3.1s-1.39 3.1-3.1 3.1h-4V17h4c2.76.0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5z&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This chapter presents a method for analyzing text data called topic modeling and applying it to the field of Library and Information Science. It describes the importance and usage of topic mining for researchers and librarians. An experiment study is also covered which applies topic modeling in a real scenario, where five model topics for the articles published in DESIDOC Journal of Library and Information Technology for the year 2017 using Topic-Modeling-Toolkit and prediction modeling is constructed using RapidMiner toolbox.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marketing of LIS Products and Services in Select Medical Libraries of Delhi in Digital Environment: A Comparative Study</title>
      <link>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manika-lamba.github.io/publication/3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract
  &lt;a href=&#34;#abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;svg class=&#34;anchor-symbol&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; height=&#34;26&#34; width=&#34;26&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 22 22&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M0 0h24v24H0z&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
      &lt;path d=&#34;M3.9 12c0-1.71 1.39-3.1 3.1-3.1h4V7H7c-2.76.0-5 2.24-5 5s2.24 5 5 5h4v-1.9H7c-1.71.0-3.1-1.39-3.1-3.1zM8 13h8v-2H8v2zm9-6h-4v1.9h4c1.71.0 3.1 1.39 3.1 3.1s-1.39 3.1-3.1 3.1h-4V17h4c2.76.0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5z&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;
    &lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article deals with the need of marketing of library products and services in medical libraries in the digital environment. It analyses the data collected from the two major medical libraries of India using GNU PSPP software and draw comparison among their marketing strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>


